# **Yu-Cheng Deng**

+1(530)302-6577 | ycdeng@ucdavis.edu | Davis, California LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/yu-cheng-deng-0413

# **CAREER OBJECTIVE**

A self-motivated team player with 2+ years of solid software development experiences, specializing in programming with Python and MATLAB. Currently seeking full-time job opportunities to fully exploit my training and skills, while making a significant contribution to the success of the company.

# **EDUCATION**

University of California, Davis

M.S. in Electrical and Computer Engineering (ECE), Overall GPA: 3.88/4.00

National Taipei University of Technology

B.S. in Electrical Engineering (EE)

Davis, CA, USA

Sep. 2018 – Jun. 2020

Taipei, Taiwan

Sep. 2014 – Jun. 2018

#### **SKILLS**

• Language Skills: Mandarin (native), English (proficient)

• Programming Languages: Python, MATLAB/Simulink, C/C++, C++/CLI, R, HTML/CSS, JavaScript

Software Development: Image Processing, Computer Vision, Object-oriented Programming, Machine Learning
Technical Skillset: Git, Bash (Shell Scripting), Open CV, SQL, .NET, Linux (Ubuntu), Windows, macOS

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

Wintec Industries

Newark, CA, USA

Jun. 2019 – Aug. 2019

**Junior Test Engineer** 

- Created a File Transfer Protocol (FTP) Server in Linux to which the operating machines can transfer the files
- Built the script written in C++/CLI to achieve the automatic file transfer through FTP
- Constructed a user-friendly Graphical User Interface (GUI) for the production line operators to use FTP
- Used Computer Vision approach for calculating the productivity of the Printed Circuit Board (PCB) and monitoring the production lines by programming Python and Open CV into Raspberry Pi 4 integrated with Pi camera

# RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

## **Graduate Researcher (Master's Research)**

Apr. 2019 - May. 2020

- Worked on "improved visualization of fiber-based fluorescence lifetime imaging (FLIm) in a Clinical Setting" research
- Applied algorithms and **image processing** to FLIm data visualization for the classification of tumors
- Proposed a robust algorithm for real-time visualization for tumor delineation based on the clinical applications
- Constructed a Graphical User Interface (GUI) tool in MATLAB for FLIm data visualization for research purposes

Coursework Project- Improvement in Reinforcement Learning for Frogger Game

Jan. 2019 - Mar. 2019

- Regenerated the arcade game "Frogger game" using PyGame in Python
- Applied the reinforcement learning (Q-learning) to the Frogger game and analyze the performance
- Exploited nearest neighbor interpolation approach to improve the performance of the Q-learning for the Frogger game

Coursework Project- Human Following Robot Based on Reactive Algorithm for Safe Navigation Jan. 2019 - Mar. 2019

- Utilized Simulink toolbox and MATLAB script to simulate the human following robot (Pioneer 3-DX) and its sensors
- Constructed a simulation environment and formulated performance analysis strategies
- Applied biological obstacle-avoidance algorithm to the robot and analyzed it in the synthetic environment

## Senior Project- Care System for Pressure Ulcer Patients

Jun. 2017 - Dec. 2017

- Exploited the Arduino sensors to measure the major factors in causing ulcers (humidity, temperature, pressure, etc.)
- Employed Arduino Wi-Fi to transmit the sensor data to IoT platforms, ThingSpeak (Web) and BLYNK (Android App)
- Used PHP with MySQL to transmit the sensor data to the database, creating webpage for the Server and Client

# LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE

Vice President - Taiwanese Graduate Student Association (TGSA) at UC Davis

Jun. 2019 - Jun. 2020

Chief Executive - Student Union of EE Dept. at National Taipei University of Technology

Sep. 2015 - Dec. 2016